Finding Aid for the Jonathan Friedlander Collection of Middle Eastern Americana LSC.1314
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Advertisements, 1892 - 1988; 1 box, 4 oversize boxes (.5 linear feet)
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1922; Item No. 27; 2 sheets: 27 x 37 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads: "Keep That Wedding Day Complexion." Includes illustration of Egyptian scene. Advertisement is from January 7, 1922 issue of Saturday Evening Post.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1927; Item No. 26; 1 sheet: 27 x 37 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads: "Stay Young with Your Daughter." Includes an illustration of an Egyptian queen.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1915; Item No. 25; 1 sheet: 25 x 35 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads: "If the Sphinx could tell her Secrets."
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1923; Item No. 24; 1 sheet: 27 x 39 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads: "Not a Day Older." Includes an illustration of an Egyptian queen and her servants.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1916; Item No. 23; 1 sheet: 25 x 39 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads: "3000 years ago – and tonight." Features an illustration of a modern-day couple juxtaposed with an illustration of an Egyptian queen being admired by two men. Advertisement is from May 1916 issue of Ladies Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1919; Item No. 22; 1 sheet: 25 x 39 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads: "After a Journey Three Thousand Years Ago." Ad features a European woman in oriental costume being offered flasks of oil by a merchant. Advertisement is from April 1919 issue of Ladies Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1922; Item No. 21; 1 sheet: 27 x 39 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads: "Better than jewels." Includes an illustration of a European woman dressed as an Egyptian queen beside flasks of oil. Advertisement is from June 1922 issue of Ladies Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1913; Item No. 20; 1 sheet: 25 x 39 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads: "For two thousand years Palm and Olive Oils have been carried over land and sea." Features an illustration of women from Ceylon and Spain pouring oils. Advertisement is from February 1913 issue of Ladies Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1918; Item No. 19; 1 sheet: 25 x 39 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads: "When Ancient Egypt was young." Features an illustration of a European woman dressed as an Egyptian queen. Advertisement is from July 1918 issue of Ladies Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1919; Item No. 18; 1 sheet: 25 x 39 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads: "Back to the Home of Olives." Features an illustration of a European woman opening a box of Palmolive products in the desert. Advertisement is from October 1919 issue of Ladies Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., undated; Item No. 17; 1 sheet: 10 x 18 centimeters, mounted color photocopy (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Ad features a European woman in oriental costume being offered flasks of oil by a merchant.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1920; Item No. 15; 1 sheet: 40 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads, "Ancient women asked their seers, and they said, "palm and olive oils". Ad is located on p. 113 of the June 1920 issue of The Ladies' Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1924; Item No. 9; 1 sheet: 36 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Includes an illustration of merchants bringing jewels to an Egyptian queen. Ad is located on p.54 of the February 1924 issue of The Ladies' Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1917; Item No. 2; 1 sheet: 42 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Ad features a woman resurrecting from an Egyptian sarcophagus, unraveling herself from mummy bandages.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1917; Item No. 3; 1 sheet: 42 x 28 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads, "No convenient corner store, no fragrant green cake, but flagons of Palm and Olive oil brought from far countries for the toilets of aristocratic women." Ad is located in the July 1917 issue of Ladies' Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1918; Item No. 4; 1 sheet: 40 x 28 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Ad features a European woman dressed as an Egyptian queen. Ad is located in the July 1918 issue of Ladies' Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1924; Item No. 5; 1 sheet: 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Features an illustration of an ancient Egyptian scene.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1920; Item No. 6; 1 sheet: 41 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads, "the beauty secret of Cleopatra hidden in every cake." Ad is located on p. 110 in the April 1920 issue of The Delineator.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1918; Item No. 16; 1 sheet: 40 x 28 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Ad features a European woman dressed as an Egyptian queen. Ad is located in the May 1918 issue of Ladies' Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1914; Item No. 8; 1 sheet: 40 x 28 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Ad features a woman dressed as an Egyptian royal servant and carrying flasks of olive and palm oils.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1920; Item No. 1; 1 sheet: 41 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Ad is located on p. 159 of the December 1920 issue of The Ladies' Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1924; Item No. 10; 1 sheet: 36 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Features an illustration of a desert caravan and women attended by slaves. Ad is located on p.54 of the April 1923 issue of Pictorial Review.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1917; Item No. 11; 1 sheet: 36 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Ad features an illustration of a slave fanning a European Cleopatra. Ad is located on p. 45 of the May 1917 edition of The Ladies' Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1917; Item No. 12; 1 sheet: 41 x 28 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Caption reads, "The elegant Egyptian had her "Palmolive" but it came by sea and caravan from far countries..." Ad is located on p. 63 of the February 1917 issue of the Ladies' Home Journal.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1924; Item No. 13; 1 sheet: 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Ad features an illustration of an American couple seated in a private balcony of an opera house, juxtaposed with an illustration of a pharaoh and his queen.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1922; Item No. 14; 1 sheet: 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Ad features a woman holding a bar of Palmolive soap juxtaposed with an image of a woman in oriental costume pouring palm oil from a flask.
  - Palmolive advertisement., 1925; Item No. 7; 1 sheet: 36 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Ad features a European woman in oriental costume being offered flasks of oil by a merchant. Ad is located on p. 46 of the July 1925 edition of The Delineator.
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement., 1913; Item No. 4; 1 sheet: 40 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 7)
    Caption reads, "Will you ever forget the delightful taste of that first Fatima"
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement., 1926; Item No. 10; 1 sheet: 17 x 25 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 7)
    Caption reads: "Not too much Turkish, not too little Turkish; neither over-rich nor commonplace... But just enough Turkish... "
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement., 1918; Item No. 7; 1 sheet: 31 x 21 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 7)
    Caption reads: "a sensible cigarette."
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement., 1913; Item No. 6; 1 sheet: 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 7)
    Ad is an illustration of an airplane and a pack of Fatima cigarettes.
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement., 1913; Item No. 5; 1 sheet: 31 x 40 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 7)
    Ad is an illustration of a group of actors smoking Fatima cigarettes on a movie set.
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement., 1928; Item No. 3; 1 sheet: 29 x 21 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 7)
    Caption reads, "They certainly do know their cigarettes, this younger crowd!"
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement., 1951; Item No. 8; 1 sheet: 35 x 26 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 7)
    Caption reads: "the difference is quality."
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement., 1915; Item No. 2; 1 sheet: 25 x 17 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 7)
    Ad features a high society couple sharing a cigarette at a masquerade ball.
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement., 1915; Item No. 1; 1 sheet: 24 x 17 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 7)
    Ad features an illustration of the 1915 Panama-Pacific International Exposition in San Francisco and reads, "The International Jury of Award selected Fatima as the only cigarette to be awarded the Grand Prix."
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement., 1918; Item No. 9; 1 sheet: 17 x 25 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement Liggett and Myers Tobacco Company., undated; Item No. 15; 1 sheet, 16 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 7)
    From caption: "Leave it to the younger crowd to know the best!"
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement Liggett and Myers Tobacco Company., undated; Item No. 14; 1 sheet, 16 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 7)
    From caption: "Of the many common-sense features about Fatima the one that seems to appeal to most men is this."
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement., 1924; Item No. 11; 1 sheet: 17 x 25 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 7)
    Caption reads: "What a whale of a difference a few cents make!"
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement., undated; Item No. 12; 1 sheet: 20 x 27 centimeters, mounted color photocopy (Box 47, Folder 7)
    Caption reads: "All America is now smoking this pleasing 'Turkish Blend' – must be that it gives better satisfaction." Features illustration of harem woman holding box of cigarettes. Advertisement is from Life magazine.
  - Fatima cigarette advertisement Liggett and Myers Tobacco Company., undated; Item No. 13; 1 sheet, 16 x 24 centimeters, shared with AO1150 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    From caption: "It is significant that so many men who once smoked expensive Turkish cigarettes return from overseas to their clubs in the lend of plenty – to buy Fatimas."
  - W. & J. Sloane rug advertisement New York, NY: W. & J. Sloane., undated; Item No. 13; 1 sheet, 16 x 24 centimeters, shared with AO1149 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    From caption: "Antique and modern Eastern rugs." Features Ghiordes prayer rug.
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., Item No. 9; 1 sheet: 24 x 17 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Ad features a couple watching a polo match and sharing a Murad cigarette.
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., 1921; Item No. 10; 1 sheet: 25 x 17 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Features an illustration of Santa Claus delivering Murad cigarettes.
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., Item No. 8; 1 sheet: 24 x 17 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Ad features a burning Murad cigarette and three women seated on its plume of smoke.
  - Murad cigarette advertisement New York, NY: Condé Nast., 1918; Item No. 11; 1 sheet: 33 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Ad features a naval officer smoking a Murad cigarette and a woman at the beach. This ad is located on the inside front cover of the August 1918 issue of Vanity Fair.
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., 1915; Item No. 7; 1 sheet: 36 x 26 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Ad features a party with men in top hats smoking Murad cigarettes.
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., 1918; Item No. 13; 1 sheet: 35 x 26 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Caption reads: "compare them."
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., Item No. 3; 1 sheet: 19 x 13 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Ad features an American GI, a bald eagle, and a pack of Murad cigarettes.
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., Item No. 12; 1 sheet: 30 x 20 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Ad features an illustration of a mountain with a pack of Murad cigarettes at the peak.
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., 1921; Item No. 16; 1 sheet: 17 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Caption reads: "Peak o' the world!"
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., Item No. 5; 1 sheet: 25 x 17 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Ad features a woman's hand, adorned with jewels, holding a Murad cigarette.
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., 1921; Item No. 17; 1 sheet: 17 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Caption reads: "Judge for Yourself!"
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., undated; Item No. 6; 1 sheet: 20 x 14 centimeters, mounted color copy (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Ad features woman holding up box of cigarettes. Ad reads: "Turkish tobacco is the World's Most Famous Tobacco for Cigarettes."
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., 1918; Item No. 15; 1 sheet: 17 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Advertisement features a poem written by a British army corporal about cigarettes entitled "Fags."
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., 1920; Item No. 14; 1 sheet: 23 x 28 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Caption reads: "Some of the several types of Turkish leaves grown in the valleys about the Black Sea, from which the wonderful Murad cigarette is made." Advertisement is from March 11, 1920 issue of Life magazine.
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., 1921; Item No. 1; 1 sheet: 25 x 16 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Ad features two horse jockeys and a pack of Murad cigarettes, "...grown in the justly famous tobacco fields of the Orient."
  - Murad cigarette advertisement New York, NY: Condé Nast., 1916; Item No. 2; 1 sheet: 33 x 25 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Ad features a woman at a vanity and a tuxedoed male companion who gazes at her while smoking a Murad cigarette. This ad is located on the inside front cover of the August 1916 issue of Vanity Fair magazine.
  - Murad cigarette advertisement., 1919; Item No. 4; 1 sheet: 19 x 13 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 8)
    Ad features an army general smoking a Murad cigarette.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1944; Item No. 1; 1 sheet: 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads "first in the service."
  - Camel cigarette advertisement Winston-Salem, NC: R. J. Reynolds Tobacco Company., undated; Item No. 29; 1 sheet, 16 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    From caption: "Cigarettes made to meet your taste!"
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1946; Item No. 14; 1 sheet: 21 x 29 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "I'll be right over!"
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1946; Item No. 15; 1 sheet: 27 x 35 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "He's one of the busiest men in town."
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1968; Item No. 20; 1 sheet: 26 x 36 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "I'd walk a mile for a Camel."
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1947; Item No. 19; 1 sheet: 26 x 36 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "Experience is the best teacher!"
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1931; Item No. 16; 1 sheet: 27 x 36 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "Unhurried Choosing." Advertisement is from April 1931 issue of Pictorial Review.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1936; Item No. 18; 1 sheet: 26 x 36 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "Never get on your nerves!" Advertisement is from February 29, 1936 issue of The Saturday Evening Post.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement Winston-Salem, NC: R. J. Reynolds Tobacco Company., undated; Item No. 30; 1 sheet, 16 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    From caption: "When it's the most exciting day at the horse show."
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1935; Item No. 13; 1 sheet: 27 x 35 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "Camels certainly make a difference!" Advertisement is from June 1935 issue of Ladies Home Journal.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1952; Item No. 12; 1 sheet: 36 x 28 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "you like them." Ad is located in the February 6, 1952 issue of The Saturday Evening Post.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1947; Item No. 2; 1 sheet: 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "more doctors smoke Camels."
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1947; Item No. 3; 1 sheet: 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Ad features Mel Parnell of the Boston Red Sox, Howard Pollet of the St. Louis Cardinals, Bob Lemon of the Cleveland Indians, and Vic Raschi of the New York Yankees.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1946; Item No. 4; 1 sheet: 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "class of '06 or '46."
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1921; Item No. 5; 1 sheet: 24 x 16 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Ad is located in May 1921 issue of Atlantic Monthly magazine.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1918; Item No. 6; 1 sheet: 24 x 16 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "man alive - listen!"
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1943; Item No. 7; 1 sheet: 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Features promotion by "Red" Hulse. Ad is located in the March 1943 issue of Esquire magazine.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1947; Item No. 8; 1 sheet: 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "your 't-zone' will tell you!" Ad is located in the February 1947 issue of Ladies Home Journal.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1962; Item No. 9; 1 sheet: 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "every inch a man's smoke."
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1988; Item No. 10; 1 sheet: 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Ad features mascot Joe Camel, a woman posed on the hood of a red sports car and the Hollywood sign in the background.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement Winston-Salem, NC: R. J. Reynolds Tobacco Company., undated; Item No. 23; 1 sheet, 16 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    From caption: "As a matter of fact."
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1943; Item No. 11; 1 sheet: 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "standard equipment." Ad is located in the February 6, 1952 issue of The Saturday Evening Post.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement Winston-Salem, NC: R. J. Reynolds Tobacco Company., undated; Item No. 28; 1 sheet, 16 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    From caption: "Camels bring to you every joy you ever looked for in a cigarette!"
  - Camel cigarette advertisement Winston-Salem, NC: R. J. Reynolds Tobacco Company., undated; Item No. 21; 1 sheet, 16 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    From caption: "When you think again that our country and the men in it must be free – have a Camel!"
  - Camel cigarette advertisement Winston-Salem, NC: R. J. Reynolds Tobacco Company., undated; Item No. 22; 2 sheets, 16 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    From caption: "Why is it that the enjoyment of Camels never fails?"
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1988; Item No. 17; 1 sheet: 25 x 33 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "Smooth Character."
  - Camel cigarette advertisement Winston-Salem, NC: R. J. Reynolds Tobacco Company., undated; Item No. 24; 1 sheet, 16 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    From caption: "Why Camel leads the world."
  - Camel cigarette advertisement Winston-Salem, NC: R. J. Reynolds Tobacco Company., undated; Item No. 25; 2 sheets, 16 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    From caption: "Here's to Camel – on a million tables!"
  - Camel cigarette advertisement Winston-Salem, NC: R. J. Reynolds Tobacco Company., undated; Item No. 26; 1 sheet, 16 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    From caption: "Camels supply cigarette contentment beyond anything you ever experienced!"
  - Camel cigarette advertisement Winston-Salem, NC: R. J. Reynolds Tobacco Company., undated; Item No. 27; 1 sheet, 16 x 24 centimeters (Box 47, Folder 9)
    From caption: "When Indian summer days are here."
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1966; 1 magazine: 27 x 34 centimeters, 104 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 1)
    Caption reads: "Camel's real taste satisfies longer!" Advertisement is on back cover of January 25, 1966 issue of Look magazine.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1945; 1 magazine: 27 x 34 centimeters, 88 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 2)
    Caption reads: "Action in the Silent Service." Advertisement is on back cover of May 26, 1945 issue of Collier's magazine.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1943; 1 magazine: 27 x 34 centimeters, 134 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 3)
    Caption reads: "They've Got What it Takes!" Advertisement is on back cover of October 4, 1943 issue of Life magazine.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1951; 1 magazine: 27 x 34 centimeters, 88 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 4)
    Caption reads: "Why did you change to Camels, Lisa Kirk?" Advertisement is on back cover of May 19, 1951 issue of Collier's magazine.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1948; 1 magazine: 27 x 34 centimeters, 114 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 5)
    Caption reads: "Lion on the loose!" Advertisement is on back cover of November 9, 1948 issue of Look magazine.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1944; 1 magazine: 27 x 34 centimeters, 80 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 6)
    Caption reads: "Young Lady with a Lens." Advertisement is on back cover of April 1, 1944 issue of Collier's magazine.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1958; 1 magazine: 27 x 34 centimeters, 90 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 7)
    Caption reads: "Have a real cigarette – have a Camel." Advertisement is on back cover of February 1, 1958 issue of the Saturday Evening Post.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1951; 1 magazine: 27 x 34 centimeters, 122 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 8)
    Caption reads: "Not one single case of throat irritation due to smoking Camels!" Features endorsements by John Wayne, Joan Crawford, and Dick Powell. Advertisement is on back cover of November 6, 1951 issue of Look magazine.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1952; 1 magazine: 27 x 34 centimeters, 110 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 9)
    Caption reads: "Why did you change to Camels, Ruth Hussey?" Advertisement is on back cover of November 4, 1952 issue of Look magazine.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1960; 1 magazine: 27 x 34 centimeters, 96 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 10)
    Caption reads: "Are you smoking more now but enjoying it less?" Features endorsement by Dick Nolan. Advertisement is on back cover of November 5, 1960 issue of the Saturday Evening Post.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1946; 1 magazine: 27 x 34 centimeters, 88 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 11)
    Caption reads: "It's a Boy!" Advertisement is on back cover of April 27, 1946 issue of Collier's magazine.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1949; 1 magazine: 27 x 34 centimeters, 146 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 12)
    Caption reads: "Give Dad a present he's sure to enjoy – a carton of mild, flavorful Camels." Advertisement is on back cover of June 13, 1949 issue of Life magazine.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1937; 1 magazine: 28 x 36 centimeters, 198 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 13)
    Caption reads: "For Digestion's Sake... Smoke Camels." Features endorsement from Dorothy Kilgallen. Advertisement is on back cover of February 1937 issue of Fortune magazine.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement Indianapolis, IN: The American Legion., 1947 October; 1 magazine: 21 x 27 centimeters, 73 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 48, Folder 14)
    Features aerial acrobat Rose Gould of the Ringling Brothers and Barnum and Bailey Circus.
  - Camel cigarette advertisement., 1939; 1 magazine: 27 x 34 centimeters, 120 pages, advertisement on back page (Box 49, Folder 1)
    Caption reads: "Let up – light up a Camel." Features endorsement from Elizabeth Hawes. Advertisement is on back cover of June 1939 issue of the American Home magazine.